Finding Aid for Arnold Weinstein papers, 1956-2013
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Writing
  - Poems
    - Manuscript
      - Various Lyrics and Poems, circa 1951-2000; .ZIP file
        - Upon Us Winter
        - Vendor
        - (untitled, Walt Whitman) I saw Walt Whitman
        - Raping Europa
        - West End Avenue (Pogo Stick West End Avenue)
        - Woman's Intuition
    - Published
      - Different Poems by The Same Author. Rome, 1960 (Box 7)
      - In Beat Coast East. New York, 1960 (Box 7)
      - In Between Worlds, Vol. 1, no. 2., Spring-Summer 1961 (Box 8)
      - In Encounter, Vol. 5, no. 3., September 1955 (Box 8)
      - In The Hunter College Echo., Spring 1951 (Box 8)
      - In New Mexico Quarterly, Vol. 33, no. 2., Summer 1963 (Box 8)
      - In PEN Montblanc Literary Gala: the Writer's Choice, 1990 (Box 8)
      - In Poetry, Vol. 87, no. 3., December 1955 (Box 8)
      - In Yale/Theatre., Summer 1968 (Box 8)
      - In Yardbird Reader Vol. 5., 1976 (Box 8)
  - Teaching Materials, 1992; 1997 (Box 8)
  - Sketches and Notes, 6 folders (Box 8)
  - What Did I Do?: the Unauthorized Autobiography by Larry Rivers with Arnold Weinstein
    - Biographical Materials, 2 folders (Box 8)
    - Manuscript
      - Complete (Box 8)
      - Drafts of Various Chapters and Sections, circa 1988-1992; .ZIP file
    - Movie Proposal and Related Materials, circa 1992; .ZIP file
    - Research Materials (Box 8)
      - Notes (Box 8)
      - Interview Transcriptions, circa 1988-1992; .ZIP file
    - Reviews, miscellaneous, 1989-2002 (Box 8)
    - What Did I Do?: the Unauthorized Autobiography (Box 8)
      (New York: 1992)
  - Miscellaneous Flyers, undated (Box 8)
- Audio-Visual Materials
  - Sound recordings
    - American Revolution (Box 11)
      - Audiocassette 1: America-More or Less, 1 audiocassettes (Box 11)
      - Audiocassette 2: American Revolution, 1 audiocassettes
        - America-More or Less (Box 11)
        - San Francisco-76 (Box 11)
      - Audiocassette 3: Lady Liberty and other songs, 1975(?) (Box 11)
    - Baby Jesus/Kill My Body (audiocassette), 1 audiocassettes (Box 11)
    - Barnyard Boogaloo (audiocassette), 1 audiocassettes
      - Some You Just Can't Kill (Box 11)
      - Because of Love of You (Box 11)
    - Cabaret Songs
      (see also Box 12)
      - Audiocassette 1: Black Max. William Bolcom and Joan Morris, recorded at Kerrytown Concert House, Ann Arbor, Mich., February 14, 1985; 1 audiocassettes (Box 11)
      - Audiocassette 2: Marlene Bateman (mezzo-soprano), Stephen Sulich (piano), 1 audiocassettes (Box 11)
      - Audiocassette 3: Raquel Hecker and Jocelyn Swigger, The Looking Glass Studios, New York, NY., April 2, 1995; 1 audiocassettes (Box 11)
      - Audiocassette 4: Sharon Mabry, 1 audiocassettes (Box 11)
      - Audiocassette 5: Killer Bees, 1 audiocassettes (Box 11)
      - Audiocassette 6: Joan Morris, 1 audiocassettes (Box 11)
      - Audiocassette 7: William Bolcom and Joan Morris, 1 audiocassettes (Box 11)
      - Audiocassette 8: Cabaret Songs, 1 audiocassettes
        - Netsky 18
        - Last Lousy Moments
        - Composers
      - Audiocassette 9: Cabaret Songs, 1 audiocassettes (Box 11)
      - Audiocassette 10: Cabaret Songs performed by unidentified, recorded, January 1992; 1 audiocassettes (Box 11)
    - Casino Paradise
      - Audiocassette 1:, 1 audiocassettes
        - Act I (Box 11)
          (first 20 minutes)
        - Act I, ii-iii. American Music Theater Festival, Philadelphia, Penn. (Box 11)
      - Audiocassette 2, 1 audiocassettes
        - Killer Bs
        - Saturday
      - Audiocassette 3: Peterson (WKCR), 1 audiocassettes (Box 11)
      - Audiocassette 4: Ballroom, December 13, 1992; 1 audiocassettes (Box 11)
      - Audiocassette 5: Casino Paradise, 1 audiocassettes (Box 11)
      - Audiocassette 6: William Bolcom and Joan Morris, June 1992; 1 audiocassettes
        - Nice Things
        - Till End
        - Ballroom
      - Audiocassette 7: Casino Paradise, 1 audiocassettes (Box 11)
      - Audiocassette 8, 1 audiocassettes
        - Can't Set You Free
          (Tony Greco)
        - Jesus
        - Night
      - Audiocassette 9: Commissioned by American Music Theater Festival, 1988; 1 audiocassettes (Box 11)
    - Dynamite Tonite
      - Audiocassette 1: Yale, 1966; 1 audiocassettes (Box 11)
      - Audiocassette 2: Dynamite-I, 1 audiocassettes (Box 11)
      - Audiocassette 3: Act I Parts 1 and 2. Yale, 1966; 1 audiocassettes (Box 11)
      - Audiocassette 4: Act II, 1 audiocassettes (Box 11)
      - Audiocassette 5: Yale, 1 audiocassettes (Box 11)
      - Audiocassette 6: Act I Parts 1 and 2, 1 audiocassettes (Box 11)
    - Final Ingredient
      - Audiocassette 1: MT, 1 audiocassettes (Box 11)
      - Audiocassette 2: David Amram/Alfred Leslie, 1 audiocassettes (Box 11)
    - Fortuna
      - Audiocassette 1: Fortuna, 1 audiocassettes (Box 11)
      - Audiocassette 2: "Money Matters" Paul Sperry, tenor; Musical Elements Bob Beaser, conductor, 1 audiocassettes (Box 11)
      - Audiocassette 3: Circus music and other songs, 1962; 1 audiocassettes (Box 11)
    - General Opera
      - Audiocassette 1: Chicago, 1977; 1 audiocassettes (Box 11)
      - Audiocassette 2: Street Opera, 1 audiocassettes (Box 11)
      - Audiocassette 3: Street Opera, Chicago, 1976; 1 audiocassettes (Box 11)
    - Lorca
      - Audiocassette 1: Lorca's Gypsy New York, 1 audiocassettes (Box 11)
      - Audiocassette 2: Lorca/Greco, 1 audiocassettes (Box 11)
    - Mahagonny
      - Audiocassette 1: Mahagonny Songspiel, 1 audiocassettes (Box 11)
      - Audiocassette 2: MT, 1 audiocassettes (Box 11)
      - Audiocassette 3: Mahagonny, 1 audiocassettes (Box 11)
      - Audiocassette 4: Terrible Food; Mahagonny, 1 audiocassettes (Box 11)
      - Audiocassette 5: Mahagonny #1, 1 audiocassettes (Box 11)
      - Audiocassette 6: Mahagonny #2, 1 audiocassettes (Box 11)
      - Audiocassette 7: Mahagonny I, 1 audiocassettes (Box 11)
      - Audiocassette 8: Mahagonny II, 1 audiocassettes (Box 11)
      - Audiocassette 9: Mahagonny and Little Mahagonny, 1 audiocassettes (Box 11)
      - Audiocassette 10: Lost in [the] Stars, 1 audiocassettes (Box 11)
      - Audiocassette 11: Mahagonny at Met; Carmen Jones, 1 audiocassettes (Box 11)
      - Audiocassette 12: Mahagonny-A. W., 1 audiocassettes (Box 11)
      - Audiocassette 13: MT, 1 audiocassettes (Box 11)
    - American Classics: William Bolcom Songs, Carole Darley (soprano) and William Bolcom (piano). Recorded at Potton Hall, Suffolk, England (CD-ROM), December 28-31, 2004 (Box 12)
    - Cabaret Songs
      - CD-ROM 1: 29 Cabaret Songs. Joan Morris (soprano) and William Bolcom (piano). Recorded live September 21, 2003 at Flea Theatre NY Tribeca. Editproof for Arnold Weinstein, October 17, 2003, 1 optical disks CDs (Box 12)
      - CD-ROM 2: Blue: the Complete Cabaret Songs of William Bolcom and Arnold Weinstein. Michelle Murray (soprano) and David Murray (piano). Recorded live at the Arizona State University Organ Hall, November 5, 2001; 1 optical disks CDs (Box 12)
      - CD-ROM 3: Cabaret Songs., 1 optical disks CDs (Box 12)
      - CD-ROM 4: Cabaret Songs Complete. Joan Morris (mezzo-soprano), William Bolcom (piano). Recorded live at the Flea Theater, New York City, September 21, 2003; 1 optical disks CDs (Box 12)
      - CD-ROM 5: Masterpieces of Cabaret: Twelve Cabaret Songs (1977-83). Jody Karin Applebaum (soprano) and Marc-Andre Hamelin (piano). Copyright, 1992; 1 optical disks CDs (Box 12)
      - CD-ROM 6: Music of William Bolcom: Let Evening Comel Briefly It Enters; Cabaret Songs, Books 3 and 4 for Centaur Records. Benita Valente (soprano), Cynthia Raim (piano), Joan Morris (mezzo-soprano), William Bolcom (piano), with Michael Tree (viola). Recorded at Lefrak Hall, Queens College, Flushing, New York, December 18-20, 1998; 1 optical disks CDs (Box 12)
      - CD-ROM 7: William Bolcom: Let Evening Come; Briefly It Enters; Cabaret Songs, Volumes 3 and 4. Benita Valente (soprano), Joan Morris (mezzo-soprano), William Bolcom (piano), Cynthia Raim (piano), Michael Tree (viola). Recorded at Lefrak Concert Hall, Queens College, Flushing, New York, December 18-20, 2001; 1 optical disks CDs (Box 12)
    - Casino Paradise
      - CD-ROM 1: American Music Theater Festival Presents Casino Paradise. Recorded at Sigma Sound Studios in Philadelphia, Penn. April 16, 1990., 1 optical disks CDs (Box 12)
      - CD-ROMs 2-3: Casino Paradise: a studio production by The University of Michigan Musical Theatre Department. Ann Arbor, Mich., February 17-20, 2000; 2 optical disks CDs (Box 12)
    - McTeague
      - Audiocassette 1: McTeague. Original sound recording, Lyric Opera of Chicago, 1992. Commentary by Alfred Glasser., 1 audiocassettes (Box 12)
      - Audiocassette 2: MT, 1 audiocassettes (Box 12)
      - Audiocassette 3: MT, 1 audiocassettes (Box 12)
      - Audiocassette 4: McTeague, 1 audiocassettes (Box 12)
      - Audiocassette 5: Act I, 1 audiocassettes (Box 12)
      - Audiocassette 6: Act II, 1 audiocassettes (Box 12)
      - Audiocassette 7: Act II, 1 audiocassettes (Box 12)
      - Audiocassette 8: Act III, 1 audiocassettes (Box 12)
      - Audiocassette 9: Act II, 1 audiocassettes (Box 12)
      - Audiocassette 10: Act II, 1 audiocassettes (Box 12)
    - Metamorphoses
      - Audiocassette 1: Metamorphoses-full production, 1973; 1 audiocassettes (Box 12)
      - Audiocassette 2: A Jane L., Ltd Presentation, 1 audiocassettes (Box 12)
      - Audiocassette 3: Set You Free, 1 audiocassettes (Box 12)
      - Audiocassette 4: Finale, 1 audiocassettes (Box 12)
      - Audiocassette 5: Parts 1 and 2, 1 audiocassettes (Box 12)
      - Audiocassette 6: Finale; Ovid; Set Me Free, 1 audiocassettes (Box 12)
      - Audiocassette 7:Ovid; Million; You and Me; Ugly, 1 audiocassettes (Box 12)
    - Monkey (Story Theatre)
      - Audiocassette 1: Monkey, 1 audiocassettes (Box 12)
      - Audiocassette 2:, November 8, 2002; 1 audiocassettes (Box 12)
      - CD-ROM 1: Monkey, 1 optical disks CDs
        - Alone
        - Seven Years
        - Earth
      - CD-ROM 2: Monkey Story, 1 optical disks CDs (Box 12)
    - Monkey King (CD-ROM) (Box 12)
    - Old Addresses: in Memory of Kenneth Koch (CD-ROM) Stephen Salters (baritone) and Michel Zobel (piano) (Box 12)
    - Party
      - Audiocassette 1: My Wife, 1 audiocassettes (Box 12)
      - Audiocassette 2: Bolcom and Morris, 1 audiocassettes (Box 12)
      - Audiocassette 3, 1 audiocassettes (Box 12)
        - Pirge
        - Party Prayer
        - Catalogue
        - Don't make Em Big Enuf
        - Suddenly
        - No Time
        - He and She
        - I Wasn't Invited
    - People are the River (audiocassette)
      - San Francisco, 1976 (Box 12)
      - Los Angeles, 1977 (Box 12)
    - Play of Consciousness
      (music by various composers)
      - Audiocassette 1: Play of Consciousness, 1 audiocassettes (Box 12)
      - Audiocassette 2: Jump Up; Play of Consciousness, 1 audiocassettes (Box 12)
      - Audiocassette 3: Evil; Marching Band, 1 audiocassettes (Box 12)
    - Rigoletto (audiocassette): Parts 1 and 2 (Box 12)
    - Shlemiel the First
      - Audiocassette 1: Folk Songs, Yiddish, 1 audiocassettes (Box 12)
      - Audiocassette 2:, March 15, 1995; 1 audiocassettes (Box 12)
        - Cradle
        - Mistake
      - Audiocassette 3, 1 audiocassettes (Box 12)
        - Papa
        - Monk's
        - Lester
      - Audiocassette 4, 1 audiocassettes (Box 12)
        - Rascal Music
        - World Beat
      - Audiocassette 5: Rascal 2, 1 audiocassettes (Box 12)
      - Audiocassette 6: Oy Vay Duet, 1 audiocassettes (Box 12)
      - Audiocassette 7: Oy Vay Love Duet, 1 audiocassettes (Box 12)
        - Rascal
        - Now Shlemiel
        - Perlman
      - Audiocassette 8: Demo, 1 audiocassettes (Box 12)
      - Audiocassette 9: Hank's Shlemiel Song, 1 audiocassettes (Box 12)
      - Audiocassette 10: Shlemiel Songs, 1 audiocassettes (Box 12)
        - Shlemiel Songs, December 1993
        - Fortuna
      - Audiocassette 11: Title Song, 1 audiocassettes (Box 12)
        - New Shlemiel Songs, December 1995
        - Shlemiel the First, Quartet
      - Audiocassette 12: Additions, 1 audiocassettes (Box 12)
        - Hanks's Chelm
    - Songs of Arnold Weinstein and Tony Greco (CD-ROM), 2004 (Box 12)
    - Tupelo ICD-ROM) (Box 12)
      (music by Anthony Davis)
    - View from the Bridge
      - Audiocassette 1: View from the Bridge, 1 audiocassettes (Box 12)
      - Audiocassette 2: View from the Bridge, 1 audiocassettes (Box 12)
      - Audiocassette 3: Arnold on NPR about "View", 1 audiocassettes (Box 12)
      - CD-ROMs 1-3: Metropolitan Opera. December 12, 2002. Dennis Russell Davies (conductor), 3 optical disks CDs (Box 12)
      - CD-ROMs 4-5: World premiere recording. Lyric Opera of Chicago, October-November 1999; 2 optical disks CDs (Box 12)
    - W. C. (audiocassette) (Box 12)
      (music by Laurence Rosenthal): Al Carmines
    - Wind in the Willows
      - Audiocassette 1: Schneider-Weill, 1 audiocassettes (Box 12)
      - Audiocassette 2: Wind in the Willows, 1 audiocassettes (Box 12)
  - Video Recordings (VHS)
    - Blue Margaritas, 1989 (Box 13)
    - Bolcom and Weinstein interviews, October 27, 1997
      - Tape 1: B[o]lcom/Weinstein interview. Piano with Morris "View from the Bridge", 1 videotapes VHS (TM) (Box 13)
      - Tape 2: Work/Interviews, 1 videotapes VHS (TM) (Box 13)
      - Tape 3: Interviews, 1 videotapes VHS (TM) (Box 13)
    - Casino Paradise, University of Michigan, February 19, 2000; 1 videotapes VHS (TM) (Box 13)
    - McTeague
      - Directed by Robert Altman, 2 videotapes VHS (TM) (Box 13)
      - Real McTeague, 1 videotapes VHS (TM) (Box 13)
      - University of Indiana, February 17, 1996; 1 videotapes VHS (TM) (Box 13)
    - Play of Consciousness, 3 videotapes VHS (TM) (Box 13)
    - William Bolcom & Joan Morris, 1 videotapes VHS (TM) (Box 13)
Related Materials
The William Bolcom and Joan Morris papers, 1960-2010 at the Bentley Historical Library (call number 0074 Aa 2 UAl). Collection includes programs, itineraries, newspaper articles and reviews of performances, as well as contracts; original scores to Bolcom's compositions, including McTeague, Casino Paradise, and A View from the Bridge; and topical files relating to awards, competitions, and other activities and interests; also CDs, audio-cassettes, and videotapes of performances.